Guide to The Alfred C. Berol Collection of Lewis Carroll 1845-1993 MSS.057
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series 6: Provenance, 108850
  - Subseries 6D: Provenance Notes, 108896
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Argles., undated; 108956 (Box 11, Folder 674)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Atkinson., undated; 108955 (Box 11, Folder 675)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Barry., undated; 108954 (Box 11, Folder 676)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to George Charles Bell., undated; 108953 (Box 11, Folder 677)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Mrs. C.F. Moberly Bell., undated; 108952 (Box 11, Folder 678)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Margaret Brough., undated; 108951 (Box 11, Folder 679)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Mary Collingwood., undated; 108950 (Box 11, Folder 680)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Sir Robert Collins., undated; 108949 (Box 11, Folder 681)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Cunnygham., undated; 108948 (Box 11, Folder 682)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Daniel., undated; 108947 (Box 11, Folder 683)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Dodgson., undated; 108946 (Box 11, Folder 684)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Draper., undated; 108945 (Box 11, Folder 685)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Drury., undated; 108944 (Box 11, Folder 686)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Beatrice Earle., undated; 108943 (Box 11, Folder 687)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Feilden., undated; 108942 (Box 11, Folder 688)
    - Provenance Notes CLD to Ffoulkes., undated; 108941 (Box 11, Folder 689)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Fletcher, undated; 108940 (Box 11, Folder 690)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Franklin., undated; 108939 (Box 11, Folder 691)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, Cld to W. George"s Sons., undated; 108938 (Box 11, Folder 692)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Girdlestone., undated; 108937 (Box 11, Folder 693)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Harcourt., undated; 108936 (Box 11, Folder 694)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Hardman., undated; 108935 (Box 11, Folder 695)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Holiday., undated; 108934 (Box 11, Folder 696)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Hunter., undated; 108933 (Box 11, Folder 697)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Hussey., undated; 108932 (Box 11, Folder 698)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Jackson., undated; 108931 (Box 11, Folder 699)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Jebb., undated; 108930 (Box 11, Folder 700)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Kish., undated; 108929 (Box 11, Folder 701)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Knight., undated; 108928 (Box 11, Folder 702)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Langbridge., undated; 108927 (Box 11, Folder 703)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Prince Leopold., undated; 108926 (Box 11, Folder 704)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Alice Liddell., undated; 108925 (Box 11, Folder 705)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Lucy., undated; 108924 (Box 11, Folder 706)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Mrs. Mallalieu., undated; 108923 (Box 11, Folder 707)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Martin-Henry., undated; 108922 (Box 11, Folder 708)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Nicholson., undated; 108921 (Box 11, Folder 709)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Patmore., undated; 108920 (Box 11, Folder 710)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Professor., undated; 108919 (Box 11, Folder 711)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Rivers., undated; 108918 (Box 11, Folder 712)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Rix., undated; 108917 (Box 11, Folder 713)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Shute., undated; 108916 (Box 11, Folder 714)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Stevens, undated; 108915 (Box 11, Folder 715)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Tidy., undated; 108914 (Box 11, Folder 716)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Todd., undated; 108913 (Box 11, Folder 717)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Walters., undated; 108912 (Box 11, Folder 718)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Ward., undated; 108911 (Box 11, Folder 719)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Webb., undated; 108910 (Box 11, Folder 720)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Whatford., undated; 108909 (Box 11, Folder 721)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Wilcox., undated; 108908 (Box 11, Folder 722)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, CLD to Yonge., undated; 108907 (Box 11, Folder 723)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, Harry Furniss to Dodgson., undated; 108906 (Box 11, Folder 724)
    - Provenance Notes, Letters, Rossetti to Dodgson., undated; 108905 (Box 11, Folder 725)
    - Provenance Notes, Manuscripts, "A Charade". (Oversize), undated; 108904 (Box 11, Folder 725A)
    - Provenance Notes, Manuscripts, "On Pleasure" and "Declamation Read in Hall"., undated; 108903 (Box 11, Folder 726)
    - Provenance Notes, Photographs, The Terry Family., undated; 108902 (Box 11, Folder 727)
    - Provenance Notes, Print Material, Eight or Nine Wise Words About Letter Writing"., undated; 108901 (Box 11, Folder 728)
    - Provenance Notes, Print Material, "An Easter Greeting"., undated; 108900 (Box 11, Folder 729)
    - Provenance Notes, Print Material, The Wonderland Postage Stamp Case., undated; 108899 (Box 11, Folder 730)
    - Provenance Notes, Print Material, Berol Collection Songs., undated; 108898 (Box 11, Folder 731)
    - Provenance Notes, Miscellaneous., undated; 108897 (Box 11, Folder 732)
  - Subseries 6E Printed Materials. (See Ovrsize Box 14)., 108851
    Scope and Contents note
    Articles on Carroll (folders 3-16), and Auction Catalogues (folders 16.1-45)
    - Ayres, H.M., "Carroll"s Withdrawal of the 1865 Alice", Nov. 1934., 108895 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Berol, A., "Lanrick - A Goame for 2 Players", 1959., 108894 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Blankc, J., "Wonderland Alice", Sept. 15, 1951., 108893 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Dickson, S., "The Bulwer-Lytton Collection", 1946., 108892 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Evans, L., "the Return of Alic"s", 1965., 108891 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Levin, H. "Wonderland Revisited", 1965., 108890 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Printing and the Mind of Men, July, 1963 (copy 1)., 108889 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Printing and the Mind of Men, July, 1963 (copy 2)., 108888 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Shaw, J.M., "The Parodies of Lewis Carroll and their Originals", Dec. 1960., 108887 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Weaver, W., "Alice"s Adventures in Wonderland its origin and its author", 1951., 108886 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Weaver, W., "The first edition of Alices"s Adventures in Wonderland, a census", 1971 (copy 1)., 108885 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Weaver, W., "The first edition of Alices"s Adventures in Wonderland, a census", 1971 (copy 2)., 108884 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Weaver, W., "The Mathematical Manuscripts of Lewis Carroll", 1954, 108883 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Weaver, W., "The Parrish Collection of Carrolliana", 1956., 108882 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - American Art Association Anderson Galleries, Inc., 1938. [folder is labeled "16"), 108881 (Box 16, Folder ID: 16.1)
    - Betram Rota Ltd., Spring 1958, 108880 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Betram Rota Ltd., Summer 1960., 108879 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Blackwell, 1953., 108878 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Christie"s, June 29, 1959; July 1, 1965., 1959,1965; 108877 (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Christie"s, June 19, 1968., 108876 (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Frank Hollings, 1943; 1946., 108875 (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, Oct. 1940., 108874 (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, Jan. 1941., 108873 (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, April & Dec. 1941., 108872 (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, Jan. & Feb. 1942., 108871 (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, Jan. & March 1945., 108870 (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, April 1945., 108869 (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, April & May 1945., 108868 (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, April 1946., 108867 (Box 17, Folder 30)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, May & Oct. 1946., 108866 (Box 17, Folder 31)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, Dec. 1947., 108865 (Box 17, Folder 32)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, May & April 1949., 108864 (Box 17, Folder 33)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, Nov. 1950., 108863 (Box 18, Folder 34)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, March & Oct. 1951., 108862 (Box 18, Folder 35)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, Nov. & Dec. 1951., 108861 (Box 18, Folder 36)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, Feb. 1952, Feb. 1953, & Dec. 1954., 1952-1954; 108860 (Box 18, Folder 37)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, Feb., April & May 1955., 108859 (Box 18, Folder 38)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, March 1960 & Nov. 1961., 1960-1961; 108858 (Box 18, Folder 39)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, March & Dec. 1962., 108857 (Box 19, Folder 40)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, May & Dec. 1963., 108856 (Box 19, Folder 41)
    - Parke-Bernet Galleries, Nov. 1964 & May 1968., 1964, 1968; 108855 (Box 19, Folder 42)
    - Ritter-Hopson Galleries, Dec. 1932., 108854 (Box 19, Folder 43)
    - Scribner"s, Cat. 137., undated; 108853 (Box 19, Folder 44)
    - Chas. J. Sawyer, Ltd., 1959., 108852 (Box 19, Folder 45)
    - Sotheby & Co., 1928, 1934, 1947. (Box 19, Folder 46)
    - Sotheby & Co., 1951, 1952. (Box 20, Folder 47)
    - Sotheby & Co., 1953, 1954, 1955. (Box 20, Folder 48)
    - Sotheby & Co., 1957. (Box 20, Folder 49)
    - Sotheby & Co., 1958. (Box 20, Folder 50)
    - Sotheby & Co., 1959, 1960. (Box 20, Folder 51)
    - Sotheby & Co., 1961, 1964, 1968. (Box 21, Folder 52)
    - Sotheby & Co., 1969, 1971. (Box 21, Folder 53)
    - Robert D. Steedman, 1963. (Box 21, Folder 54)
    - Swann Auction Galleries, April 1951. (Box 21, Folder 55)
- Oversize - Series 2, 108841
  - Subseries 2B: Corrected Proofs, 108844
    - Dodgson, Charles Euclid Proofs with Ms Corrections, 4pp [n.p.] [n.d.] (X 150, X 150a, X 151, X 151a) 17 x 11., undated; 1903; 108849 (Box 12, Folder 511A)
    - Dodgson, Charles Symbolic Logic Proofs with Ms Corrections, 2pp [n.p.] [n.d.] Not numbered by Frost but "86134" in upper right of each page. 17 x 5.5., undated; 1904; 108848 (Box 12, Folder 511B)
    - Dodgson, Charles Proofs for Symbolic Logic Proofs with Ms Corrections, 6pp [n.p.] [n.d.]. 17.5 x 6., undated; 1906; 108847 (Box 12, Folder 511C)
    - Dodgson, Charles Proofs for Symbolic Logic Proofs with Ms Corrections, 6pp [n.p.] [n.d.] Set is held together with a tack., undated; 108846 (Box 12, Folder 511C)
    - Dodgson, Charles Proofs for The Game of Logic Proofs with Ms Corrections, 2pp [n.p.] [n.d.]., undated; 108845 (Box 12, Folder 511C)
  - Subseries 2C: Manuscripts by others., 108842
    - Dodgson, Margaret "Miss Jones" Song Ms, 2pp [n.p.] [n.d.] (XX 567)., undated; 108843 (Box 12, Folder 511)
- Oversize - Series 3, 108838
  - Subseries 3B: Drawings by others, 108839
    - Furniss, Harry Untitled Drawings, 1p [n.p.], [n.d.] Proofs for Sylvie and Bruno with Dodgson holograph Commentary., undated; 108840 (Box 12, Folder 542A)
- Oversize - Series 4, 108832
  - Subseries 4A., 108833
    - Photo of [Terry, Ellen] Contemporary Photographic Print, Negative Number [n.n] Figure in a carriage. Labelled "At Moray Lodge". Photo of Florence on verso. Mounted on pasteboard. on loan., undated; 2035; 108837 (Box 12, Folder 595A)
    - Dodgson, Charles Photo of Terry, Ellen and Kate Contemporary Photographic Print, Negative Number none Ellen holds rope Kate bound as Andromeda. Photo of Florence on verso. Mounted on pasteboard on loan., undated; 2036; 108836 (Box 12, Folder 595A)
    - Dodgson, Charles Photo of Terry, Florence Contemporary Photographic Print, Negative Number [n.n] Girl pares fruit with one foot up on box. 8x10. Photos of Kate and Ellen on verso. Mounted on pasteboard on loan., undated; 2037; 108835 (Box 12, Folder 595A)
    - Dodgson, Charles Photo of Terry Family Contemporary Photographic Print, Negative Number[n.n] At the family"s home in Kentish Town on July 15th, 1865. Mounted on Pasteboard 9.5 x 12., 2038; 108834 (Box 12, Folder 595B)
- Oversize - Series 5, 108803
  - Subseries 5A., 108830
    - Poster for Guinness, Callard and Bowser (12pp)., undated; 108831 (Box 12, Folder 609)
  - Subseries 5C: Ephemera., 108819
    - The Hollyn Cut-Outs., undated; 108829 (Box 12, Folder 636A)
    - Moser, Barry Print., undated; 108828 (Box 12, Folder 636B)
    - Unknown Panorama., undated; 108827 (Box 12, Folder 640A)
    - (1) Alice and the White Rabbit Macmillan Advertisng Poster, undated; 108826 (Box 13, Folder 637B (Berol Room))
    - (2)The Dodo Presenting the Thimble to Alice Macmillan Advertisng Poster., undated; 108825 (Box 13, Folder 637B (Berol Room))
    - (3) The Chesire Cat Macmillan Advertisng Poster., undated; 108824 (Box 13, Folder 637B (Berol Room))
    - (4) The Mad Tea Party Macmillan Advertisng Poster., undated; 108823 (Box 13, Folder 637B (Berol Room))
    - (5) The Mock Turtle"s Story Macmillan Advertisng Poster., undated; 108822 (Box 13, Folder 637B (Berol Room))
    - (6)The Trial of the Knave of Hearts Macmillan Advertisng Poster, undated; 108821 (Box 13, Folder 637B (Berol Room))
    - Unknown Wonderland Biscuit Tin (shelved in its own box [10a])., undated; 108820 (Box 10a, Folder 637C)
  - Subseries 5D: Magazines with Articles on Dodgson and/or his works., 108807
    - The Bakers Dozen., undated; 108818 (Box 14, Folder 645A)
    - Colliers Magazine April 9, 1949., 108817 (Box 14, Folder 645B)
    - The Jabberwock 1888-1898 1932., 108816 (Box 14, Folder 645C)
    - The Knight Letter 1974-1985., 108815 (Box 14, Folder 645)
    - Life Magazine June 18, 1951 December 25, 1950 June 29, 1959., 1951-1959; 108814 (Box 14, Folder 645E)
    - News From Home: The Firemasters of Charleston 1945., 108813 (Box 14, Folder 645)
    - The Queen November 18, 1931., 108812 (Box 14, Folder 645G)
    - Realities 1967., 108811 (Box 14, Folder 645H)
    - Ringling Brother"s Magazine 1945., 108810 (Box 14, Folder 645I)
    - Scientific American April, 1956., 108809 (Box 14, Folder 645J)
    - What"s New #197, 1956., undated; 108808 (Box 14, Folder 645K)
  - Subseries 5G: Theater Materials., 108804
    - Theater Posters for dramatizations of Alice., undated; 108806 (Box 14, Folder 653A)
    - Poster made for opening of collection at Bobst., undated; 108805 (Box 14, Folder 653B)
- Oversize - Series 6, 108788
  - Subseries 6D: Provenance Notes, 108801
    - Provenance information on Dodgson manuscript "A Charade"., undated; 108802 (Box 14, Folder 725A)